Inventory of the Department of Military Science Records 1918-2011
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Department of Military Science Records 1918-[ongoing]
Special Collections Research Center
00/02/01/22/UA 210
0.60
This collection includes invitations, material about the Queen's Guard and ROTC, and other publications from the Department of Military Science and other military-related bodies at the College of William and Mary. The collection also includes material related to the Student Army Training Corps stationed on campus during World War I, activities of other units during World War II, and the US Coast Guard Auxiliary.
Dept. of Military Science; Student Army Training Corp. arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers.
Custodial History
This collection was formerly part of the University Archives Publications Collection.
Historical Note
Information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/Dept. of Military Science
Scope and Contents
This collection includes invitations, material about the Queen's Guard and ROTC, and other publications from the Department of Military Science and other military-related bodies at the College of William and Mary. The collection also includes material related to the Student Army Training Corps stationed on campus during World War I, activities of other units during World War II, and the US Coast Guard Auxiliary.
Arrangement of Materials
Arranged alphabetically.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
College of William and Mary. Dept. of Military Science
Genre/Form of Material:
Fliers (printed matter)
Topical Term:
College of William and Mary--History--20th century.; College of William and Mary--Reserve Officer Training Corps; College of William and Mary--Students.; Invitations.; Newsletters.; Pamphlets; World War, 1914-1918--United States.; World War, 1939-1945--United States
Detailed Description of the Collection
- id56881 (Box 1)
  - Army Specialized Training Unit, 3321st, 1943-1944; id56884 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Berets, Black, 1981-1990; id56885 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Book List, 1970s; id56886 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cadet Clarion, 1981-1984; id56887 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Codewords, 1984-1997; id56888 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Faculty, Memoranda to, 1949-1986; id56889 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Military Ball, 1953-1958; id56890 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Queen's Guard, 1961-2005; id56891 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Reserve Forces Act of 1955, 1955-1956; id56892 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Reserve Officers Training Corps, 1961-2006; id56893 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Reserve Officers Training Corps Commencement Programs, 1959-1996; id56894 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Revolutionary Guard Battalion, 2001; id56895 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Selective Service Information, 1952; id56900 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Commissioning Ceremony 1987, id111592 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- id109520 (Box 2)
  - Student Army Training Corps, 1918; id56908 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Taps"; published in memory of the Students' Army Training Corps at William and Mary College, Williamsburg, Virginia, "Oh Happy Days!", December 1918; id58985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - US Coast Guard Auxiliary, 2011; id87073 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The Vulcan, 1970-1972; id56913 (Box 2, Folder 3)